Friendship Citizens Association 083
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Friendship Citizens Association Records
1944-1963
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Friendship Citizens Association
083
0.5 Linear feet
1 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
In 1892, a group of concerned Washington, D.C. residents joined together to form an organization that they felt would help meet the needs of Friendship Heights, Tenleytown, and other surrounding neighborhoods. Originally called the Northwest Suburban Citizens Association, the Friendship Citizens Association (FCA) sought to bring about new and improved fire stations, police departments, schools, and recreation areas in D.C., particularly in Northwest. It is not known exactly when the Association ceased to exist, though the most recent references to the organization in the Washington Evening Star and Washington Post are from the early to to mid-1980s. In the late 1940s and early 1950s, the FCA was first among the District's citizens groups to ask for a library in the Tenley-Friendship area. Though controversial, the city Commissioners decided to build the new library on the playground of the Janney School on Wisconsin Avenue.
Custodial History
Richard A. Williams, a former member of the Friendship Citizens Association, donated these materials to the Library in 1984.
Related Materials
Collection #040: District of Columbia Public Library Records; Collection #028: Federation of Citizens Associations of the District of Columbia Records
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of correspondence, programs, newsletters, meeting minutes, resolutions, and other materials related to the Friendship Citizens Association of Washington, D.C. The construction of a new D.C. Public Library branch in the Tenley-Friendship neighborhood was of particular interest to the Association.
Neighborhoods; Associations, institutions, etc; Organizational Records; Minutes (Records); District of Columbia. Public Library; Citizens' Associations
- Series 1
  - Appeals and Amendments, 1954-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Constitution, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - DC Presidential Vote, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - List of People Living in Friendship Area, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Map, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1946-1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Meeting Space Applications, 1951-1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, 1954-1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Resolutions, 1948-1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tenley-Friendship Library, 1944-1957 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Tenley-Friendship Library, 1944-1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)